Kevin Won

San Francisco Bay Area



kevinwon30@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/kevinwon30

Summary

Experienced Quality Assurance Automation Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the internet industry. Skilled in Software Documentation, Chrome Developer Tools, Web Applications, Quality Assurance, and Testing. Strong quality assurance professional graduated from San Francisco State University.

Experience

Quality Assurance Automation Engineer

Indeed

Jan 2021 - Mar 2023 (2 years 3 months)

- Owned test automation for service that powers job recommendations on Indeed's Home Page Job Feed
- Achieved a minimum of 80% code coverage for multiple projects by developing unit, integration, and end-to-end tests that live in the application repository written in Java
- Collaborated with engineers to define requirements, testing needs, and strategies to increase code coverage
- Led release management to help cut builds, find flaws in automated processes, track down broken tests, debug deployment issues, monitor releases, and migrated multiple projects from Jenkins to GitLab CI/CD
- Worked with engineers to automate the entire release pipeline for push-on-green
- Refactored in-house Python testing framework to eliminate flakiness and overhead maintenance by writing stable integration tests within the application code
- Integrated SonarQube with GitLab CI/CD to measure code coverage that resulted in tech debt for code clean-up and refactoring
- Held engineers accountable during code reviews by checking for unit and integration test coverage

? Quality Assurance Engineer

Indeed

Aug 2017 - Dec 2020 (3 years 5 months)

- Worked with engineers and data scientists to deploy machine learning models to help Indeed measure low-value and unqualified applications, leading to better applicant quality
- Experienced in backend testing and knowledgeable with REST APIs and gRPC
- Led release management in deploying and monitoring releases to QA and production environments (Datadog), then directing the QA team through verifying features, bug fixes, and regression tests
- Experienced in multiple tools (including internal) to investigate errors and other suspicious behavior by tracing network requests, tailing console and server logs (developer tools and terminal), modifying cookies, health checking servers, and monitoring proctor test groups
- Onboarded 4 QA engineers, 1 automation engineer, and 1 QA manager to the team, leading them through best practices, and adopting a shift-left testing mentality toward a push-on-green initiative for CI/CD

- Identified testability issues with the QA environment and received engineering and automation support to build new tools to generate test data

QA Engineer

Zillow

Jul 2016 - Jul 2017 (1 year 1 month)

- -Created & maintained functional automation scripts in Java using Selenium WebDriver to test rentals posting path
- -Responsible for weekly production deployments using Jenkins
- -Supported release of internal admin and debug tools used to syndicate listings to all three of Zillow Group brands
- -Triaged customer support tickets through Zendesk and worked with Engineers towards hotfix releases
- -Ran multiple A/B tests to increase conversion rates of landlords posting and activating their rental listings
- -Released new video feature on mobile apps to provide landlords with video walkthrough for potential renters
- -Performed RESTful API testing using Swagger on web services to post and activate rental listings

QA Engineer

NRG Home Solar

May 2015 - Jul 2016 (1 year 3 months)

- -Spearheaded QA for Marketing by testing new campaigns and landing pages for lead generation sites
- -Launched B2C web portal to customers and deployed new features to improve user experience
- -Automated front-end testing in JavaScript from lead creation to referral integration using Selenium WebDriver
- -Created acceptance tests for CRM replacement to meet functional and design specifications and requirements
- -Executed API testing of web services on logins and lead generation forms using Postman REST client
- -Rotated as troubleshooter to support production breaks of internal tools to ensure timely resolution of issues

QA Engineer

Moovweb

Aug 2014 - Mar 2015 (8 months)

- -Supported live-site maintenance to top brands like Men's Wearhouse, Forever 21, GNC, Petco, Peet's, and over 50+ clients on more than 90+ mobile sites
- -Collaborated closely with Developers, Account Managers, and Clients to communicate implementation progress, discuss blocker issues, and report product fixes
- -Automated front-end sanity checks through e-commerce checkout flows in JavaScript using Selenium WebDriver
- -Improved e-commerce conversion rates by performing A/B testing on different site layouts
- -Encouraged ease-of information accessibility by keeping GitHub wiki and readme pages updated

QA Engineer

Appurify, Inc. (Acquired by Google)

Apr 2014 - Jul 2014 (4 months)

- -Provided key performance insights of web/native apps on mobile devices to Product and Engineering teams by executing test automation scripts
- -Expanded mobile device lab to 200+ devices by deploying new iOS and Android devices to network infrastructure
- -Worked with DevOps to solve and troubleshoot device, platform, wireless and network issues



Software QA Engineer

Oct 2012 - Mar 2014 (1 year 6 months)

- -Initiated functional testing of Aspera's new high-speed file sharing and syncing desktop application
- -Supported client & server side applications by performing functional, regression & performance testing on daily builds
- -Automated user logins and application configuration settings using Selenium IDE to accelerate test efficiency

Education



App Academy

Full Stack Software Engineer

May 2023 - Oct 2023

Full-Time Software Engineering Track with a total of 960 clock hours over a 24-week course.



San Francisco State University

Skills

JavaScript • Python • React.js • Redux.js • Flask • SQLAlchemy • JaCoCo • Gradle • Java • Spring Boot